X

English

* Deutsch
* English
* Español
* Français
* Italiano
* Nederlands
* Português

Explore

* Explore
* Gallery
* Noteworthy
* Groups
* Keywords
* Community

* * *

*   [Display](javascript: showBGmenu('block'); "Display settings")

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
|     |     | Page color |
|     |     | Comments Panel |
|     |     | Screen Margins |     |
| ▼▲  |     |     |     |
|     |     | Widescreen |     |

 Example of the widescreen option

ok

X

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Ξ   | Frame Options |     |     |
| 3<br><br>\-<br><br>+ |     |     |     |

Text Size Options

ipernity  ipernity  ipernity

 **See also...** [The ima team](http://www.ipernity.com/user/team)

Privacy Policy
==============

### Privacy Statement

ipernity cares about the protection of your personal data. Since we want you to feel save within the community we are absolutely concerned about your privacy and do whatever is needed to protect it. We are subject to French and European laws, particularly the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), a declaration on the collection and processing of your personal data has been passed on to the CNIL (French "Commission Nationale Informatique et Libertés").  

Our site provides links to other websites and advertisements. This privacy statement is related to our website only and not to those of third parties.  

### Personal Data

Information that can help to identify your identity is personal data. This includes for instance your name, address and others. General information that can’t be used to identify you (such as the browser you use) is not personal data.  

### Use of personal data

Using ipernity requires the collecting of nominative information about our users. This information is necessary to:  

* personalize and optimize your use of the service
* send you your login ID in case of loss
* conform to the legislation in force (regarding your mailing address)

If you visit our website the server therefore saves the IP-address of your Internet service provider, the sites you visit within ipernity as well as date and duration of your visit. These data are required for security reasons.  

### Account information, data access, and the right to manage and delete data

* ipernity gathers two types of information via forms or cookies (see below) : nominative data and electronic ID data.  
    A. Personal data  
    This is the information you transmit to us via forms when you sign up. It is accessible and modifiable only by you through your Profile privacy settings.  
    These data include the following:  
    
* your email address
* your first and last Name
* your date of birth
* The electronic identification data  
    B. Electronic identification data  
    Electronic identification data files are used to record for instance your user preferences. These are called Cookies (see below).  
    Besides of that we save the data you used for registration as well as those for payments. Both are needed for membership reasons and the fulfillment of the contract as described in the terms of use. If you take part within the community as for example by uploading photos, videos, sounds and text we save these data in relation to you and publish them using your username.  
    
* In your Profile privacy settings you can control who is able to see different parts of your profile, including but not limited to, your email address, name, current city and other information you choose to make public.
* In your Settings you can also select which of your photos are visible to which audience (public or limited groups or distinct levels of audiences such as friends or family). On each photo page, you will also find more granular controls to change each photo setting.
* We are not using personal data or photos for targeted advertising.
* We are using depersonalized user / membership statistics in order to optimize our service.
* We will request that third-party sites respect your settings, but these parties are not under our control and updating may take some time.
* In conformity with General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the French law n° 78-17 from January 6, 1978, you may access at any time the personal information relating to you retained by Ipernity, request to have it modified or deleted. This way you may request the information relating to you to be rectified, completed, clarified, updated or deleted when inaccurate, incomplete, unclear, outdated or of which the collection, use, communication or storage is forbidden.  
    You can send your request by mail at the following address:  
    IMA  
    16, Rue Marie Gausson,  
    94350 Villiers-sur-Marne,  
    France  
    In conformity with General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the French law on information technology and liberties from January 6, 1978, we inform you that the personal data gathered via a form on ipernity can in no case be transmitted, either freely or to third parties. However, based on laws we have to obtain we are bound to forward your personal data to government agencies (such as the office of public prosecutor) in certain cases.  
    
* If you unsubscribe ipernity your data will be deleted within 6 months if possible and approved by law. Especially the data you used for subscription, uploaded media and messages will be deleted. Law requires that some of the data such as payment data have to be saved for a longer period.
* Your comments will be saved even if you unsubscribe. The same applies to your newsletter settings.

### Cookies

* Ipernity is using cookies.
* A Cookie is a text file that saves information related to your Internet browsing. This file is placed on your hard drive when you consult a website and cannot contain any virus or be executed. It is not active. Furthermore you can read the file, delete it or edit it. A Cookie cannot be used to retrieve personal data from your hard drive or read your Email address. As with everything regarding the Internet you remain anonymous as long as you wish to be. No Web site will know who you are until the moment you let it know (Identification by Login and Password).
* In no case will you ever be identified by Ipernity.com or be part of a classified file.

### The use of Cookies on Ipernity

* Generally speaking the Cookies used by ipernity save information related to the browsing of your computer on our site (the pages consulted, the date and time of consultation, etc.) that are remembered for your following visits. They contain the most recent information you have provided to us. This way when visiting us next time you will not need to fill out the proposed form again.
* Of particular importance are the following four Cookies:
* a) Two "session" Cookies: they are created upon signing in to Ipernity.com and destroyed automatically upon closing the browser. Notably they enable the site to recognize the language and time zone used.
* b) An authentication Cookie: allows the site to recognize you as a registered user but does not replace your login ID. This cookie lasts 10 days if you tick the option "Remember me" or else 4 hours.
* c) A memory Cookie of your user preferences. This cookie lasts 1000 days.
* If you are an ipernity user, you must accept cookies.
* By blocking cookies you will not be able to sign in.

### Location information and EXIF data

* Exchangeable image file format (‘EXIF’) data is a record of the settings and other relevant metadata inserted by a digital camera or device when you take a photo or video, such as camera or device type, aperture, shutter speed, focal length, and location.
* Unless you turn off EXIF data on your camera or device or remove it from the picture before uploading to ipernity, ipernity receives and stores EXIF data for all photos or videos. By default, ipernity displays the EXIF data about photos or video you upload.
* When you upload a photo or video with geographical data (i.e. from a mobile device) or manually geo-tag your photo or video, the photo or video’s location can be shown on a map.
* You can choose to hide this EXIF information from other users in Profile privacy settings under the Content settings tab.

### Newsletter

If you have signed up for ipernity’s Info Newsletter then ipernity will use the data that you have submitted in the registration process to send you the ipernity Info Newsletter or ipernity Special Newsletter. Your data will not be passed on to third parties.  

Users who no longer wish to receive our Newsletter or promotional emails will find a link at the bottom of every email sent by ipernity, with instructions to click “here”, in order to unsubscribe from the Newsletter or withdraw from receiving promotional emails.  

### Google Analytics, Google Maps

* This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies" which are text files placed on your computer to help the website analyze how users use the site. (See above about Cookies.)
* The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. In case of activation of the IP anonymization, Google will truncate/anonymize the last octet of the IP address for Member States of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to and shortened by Google servers in the USA. On behalf of the website provider Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage to the website provider.  
    Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.  
    You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. Furthermore you can prevent Google’s collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under  
    https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB.  
    Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at  
    http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb/  
    
* Please note that on this website, Google Analytics code is supplemented by “gat.\_anonymizeIp();” to ensure an anonymized collection of IP addresses (so called IP-masking).
* Google is member of the EU/US Safe Harbor Program (www.export.gov/safeharbor/) and fulfills US data privacy terms for notification, alternatives, forwarding, security, data integrity, access and implementation.
* This website uses Google Maps API to visually display geographic information. When using Google Maps, Google also collects, processes and uses data about the use of map features by visitors. For more information about Google's data processing, please refer to the Google Privacy Notice ([myaccount.google.com/privacy).](https://myaccount.google.com/privacy).) There you can also change your personal privacy settings in the privacy center.
* For detailed instructions on how to manage your own data related to Google products: [myaccount.google.com/general-light?pli=1](https://myaccount.google.com/general-light?pli=1)

### Data security

We as well as our service providers care about the security of our equipment, especially our servers. Our website is hosted at AWS.  

We are anxious to improve the already high standards of our service providers and keep up with technical developments. Transmissions from your computer to our servers via Internet are out of our control and might be insecure. It might happen that third persons change or delete e-mails or inputs you do in forms on your website. If you want to avoid any risks regarding those transmissions you can send us ideas, wishes or suggestions by letter post to the address you find within the imprint. All of the data that you submit during registration, when you log on, and during all payment transactions is transmitted using encryption.  

### Data protection officer and Information

We, the operators of ipernity.de, ipernity.com, ipernity.es, ipernity.fr and ipernity.it committed ourselves to this privacy policy. If you have questions about the use of your personal data please contact our data protection officer. He/she will be available for any suggestion, information request and complaint. You may find the name and address of our data protection officer here: [www.ipernity.com/user/team](https://www.ipernity.com/user/team)  

Last update 2021-03-19  

* * *

* * *

* * *

ipernity © 2007-2024

Help & Contact | Club news | About ipernity | History | ipernity Club & Prices | Guide of good conduct  
[Donate](javascript:ClkDonate() "PayPal - The safer, easier way to pay online!") | Group guidelines | Privacy policy | Terms of use | Statutes | In memoria

* * *

* * *

|     |     |
| --- | --- |

**Your browser seems too old or javascript is deactivated.** Please use a recent browser:

[See "Cookies" section in Privacy policy](http://www.ipernity.com/about/you) Allow
